Contact

michael.lopez@hcahealthcare .com

www.linkedin.com/in/michael-a-lopez-193b905 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Team Building Leadership Healthcare

Certifications CCRN CEN

Michael A. Lopez

Chief Nursing Officer at Heart Hospital of Austin- HCA Healthcare CWT Division

Austin, Texas Area

Summary

I am a highly competitive, results-oriented, healthcare professional with twelve years of proven leadership ability. I have a passion for healthcare leadership and maintain an endless commitment to excellence in patient care. I believe that my critical care skills, coupled with my leadership experiences, provide a solid foundation of competency. My ability to remain highly organized in a fast-paced setting, paired with my collaborative spirit and team approach, has allowed me to instill credibility effectively, and trust amongst my staff and colleagues. My commitment to quality patient care coupled with my business-minded approach has proven to be my strengths in my current leadership roles and will differentiate my leadership.

Experience

HCA Healthcare-Heart Hosptial of Austin Chief Nursing Officer May 2018 - Present (2 years 1 month)

St. David's Georgetown Hospital Chief Nursing Officer July 2015 - May 2018 (2 years 11 months)

HCA/St.David's Central West Texas Division-SAMC Associate Chief Nursing Officer June 2013 - August 2015 (2 years 3 months) Austin, Texas Area

Seeking the opportunity to continue in a leadership role as a Chief Nursing Officer.

Personal Vision Statement

To be a respected leader within my organization through development of collaborative partnerships which improve quality of patient care and positively impact patient experiences.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Operations management
- Team Building
- Leadership and mentoring
- Process efficiency identification

Fiscal Stewardship

- Physician and Staff Relations
- Conflict Resolution
- Change agent

QRx Medical Management Vice President of Operations-Emergency Services March 2012 - June 2013 (1 year 4 months) Dallas Texas

HCA North Texas-LCMC

Administrative Director of Emergency Services & Cardiology April 2007 - March 2012 (5 years)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Education

The University of Texas at Arlington

Texas Woman's University
MBA, Health Care Administration/Management